In this American English pronunciation video,
在这段美式英语发音视频中，
we're going to learn how to make the two TH sounds.
我们将学习如何发出两种TH音。
These sounds are paired together because they take the same mouth position.
这些音被放在一起是因为它们使用相同的口腔位置。
Th is unvoiced, meaning only air passes through the mouth.
Th是无声的，意味着只有空气通过口腔。
And TH is voiced,
而TH是有声的，
meaning you make a sound with the vocal cords.
意味着你用声带发出声音。
TH,
TH，
TH.
TH。
The very tip of the tongue comes through the teeth.
舌尖要伸出牙齿。
The air passes around the tongue.
空气绕过舌头。
The tongue is relaxed.
舌头是放松的。
There shouldn't be any pressure in the mouth or a stop quality to this sound.
口腔中不应有任何压力或停顿的感觉。
Just nice and easy.
就是轻松自然。
Th, th.
Th, th。
The tongue has to easily vibrate between the teeth,
舌头必须在牙齿之间轻松振动，
so keep the tongue soft and relaxed.
所以保持舌头柔软和放松。
Th, th.
Th, th。
The lips don't affect this sound,
嘴唇不影响这个音，
so they can be transitioning to the next sound.
所以它们可以过渡到下一个音。
For example, in the THR cluster,
例如，在THR音群中，
the lips will round a little bit for the R as you make the TH.
当你发TH音时，嘴唇会稍微为R音圆起来。
Three,
three.
three。
Be careful with the tongue tip.
小心舌尖。
Make sure it doesn't come too far forward.
确保它不要伸得太远。
It's just the very tip that should come between the teeth.
只有舌尖应该在牙齿之间。
To make the unvoiced TH,
要发无声的TH，
the tongue tip absolutely has to come through the teeth.
舌尖绝对要伸出牙齿。
Th, th.
Th, th。
But the voiced TH can be different,
但有声的TH可以不同，
when it's in an unstressed,
当它在一个不重读的，
quick word like these,
快速的词中时，比如these，
or the.
或the。
The tongue tip doesn't have to come through the teeth.
舌尖不必伸出牙齿。
It can press behind the teeth.
它可以压在牙齿后面。
Make sure the tongue isn't at the roof of the mouth,
确保舌头不在口腔顶部，
or pointing down, but pressing right in the middle.
或向下指，而是压在中间。
Where the teeth come together.
在牙齿合拢的地方。
If it's not in the right position,
如果位置不对，
the sound will be wrong.
声音就会不对。
Th, th.
Th, th。
These.
These。
Th.
Th。
This tongue shortcut works in these words because they're unstressed.
这个舌头的捷径在这些词中有效，因为它们是不重读的。
So when you don't bring your tongue tip through the teeth,
所以当你不把舌尖伸出牙齿时，
it allows you to make these less important words quickly.
这让你可以快速发出这些不太重要的词。
These.
These。
Th.
Th。
Let's look at these sounds up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这些声音。
Notice how it's just the very tip that comes out of the teeth.
注意只有舌尖伸出牙齿。
The tongue is relaxed,
舌头是放松的，
the teeth surround it,
牙齿围绕着它，
but they're not clamping down on it.
但没有夹住它。
The lips and face are relaxed.
嘴唇和面部是放松的。
Throw.
Throw。
Notice how the lips are starting to flare for the R as the tongue comes through the teeth for the unvoiced TH.
注意当舌头伸出牙齿发无声的TH时，嘴唇开始为R音张开。
Birthday.
Birthday。
Keep in mind, when you only stick the very tip of your tongue out,
记住，当你只伸出舌尖时，
the movement into other sounds isn't as hard as you might think.
进入其他音的动作并不像你想象的那么难。
Watch the tongue tip come in and flip up for the D.
看舌尖进来并翻上去发D音。
This is a quick move of the tongue that you can practice over and over to make it more natural.
这是一个快速的舌头动作，你可以反复练习以使其更自然。
Brother.
Brother。
Tongue tip through the teeth for the voiced TH.
舌尖伸出牙齿发有声的TH。
Lips and tongue are relaxed.
嘴唇和舌头是放松的。
Worth.
Worth。
Ending in the unvoiced TH.
以无声的TH结尾。
Again,
再次，
the lips and tongue look very relaxed.
嘴唇和舌头看起来非常放松。
Remember to keep your tongue relaxed and soft when you practice this sound.
记住在练习这个音时保持舌头放松和柔软。
The voiced and unvoiced TH.
有声和无声的TH。
Throw.
Throw。
Birthday.
Birthday。
Brother.
Brother。
Worth.
Worth。
Example words.
示例词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Other.
Other。
Th.
Th。
Other.
Other。
Either.
Either。
Th.
Th。
Though.
Though。
Th.
Th。
Though.
Though。
Thursday.
Thursday。
Th.
Th。
Thursday.
Thursday。
Nothing.
Nothing。
Th.
Th。
Nothing.
Nothing。
South.
South。